<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:15:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publication identifiers are great!</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2023-12-08-publication-identifiers-are-great/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2023-12-08-publication-identifiers-are-great/</guid><description>Recently, I needed to generate a consistently formatted publication list from a rather unstructured input. The idea was to take the growing list of publications from the consortium in which I am employed, and create a script able to regenerate and restructure it with as little manual labour as possible, while producing metadata reusable in other contexts. It took me on a deeper than intended delve into identifiers, APIs, and regular expressions, but what came out of it was pretty satisfying.</description></item><item><title>Exploring film simulations</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2023-03-26-exploring-film-simulations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 19:45:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2023-03-26-exploring-film-simulations/</guid><description>In the prime days of analog photography, some photographic fims earned a legendary status. FujiChrome Velvia and Astia from Fujifilm, or Kodachrome from Kodak became big names. As a kid discovering photography as a hobby, I may have only had Agfa Vista and Kodak Gold to choose from at the local photo lab, but I sure did read about the others.
Now that we are into the era of smartphone photography, and digital cameras are often associated with vlogging, I think Fujifilm does an outstanding job marketing-wise by advertising &amp;#34;film simulation modes&amp;#34;: color profiles that are applied directly by the camera to jpeg images.</description></item><item><title>Circular pour-over</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-12-09-pourover/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 23:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-12-09-pourover/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, James Hoffman posted &amp;#34;A better 1 cup V60 Technique&amp;#34;, an update to his &amp;#34;Ultimate V60 technique&amp;#34; adjusted to smaller servings. I was pleasantly surprised that the 1 cup technique is more simialr (very similar, in fact) to the technique I&amp;#39;ve been using for a long time; that is, the drip recipe from The Barn. Have we gone full circle?
The Barn was pretty much my gateway into speciality coffee, back during my university years (around 2015, probably).</description></item><item><title>E-mail in Emacs with Notmuch</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-11-20-emacs-notmuch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 16:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-11-20-emacs-notmuch/</guid><description>I switched to reading and writing my e-mail in Emacs with Notmuch. The first impressions are good – I like the simplicity brought by text interface, and the workflow focused on tagging, archiving, and searching.
There is a ton of blog posts on configuring e-mail in Emacs already (I link several at the end). One thing that was important for me and not easy to find was S/MIME signing, so I will describe it in more detail, and be more concise about other aspects.</description></item><item><title>From my font folder</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-06-17-fonts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-06-17-fonts/</guid><description>I spend a large part of my workday staring at a text on a computer screen. Sometimes, I also need to produce some text that needs to be beamed onto a wall, plotted onto a large piece of paper, or printed on a bunch of A4s. I like when these things look nice.
Polish type designer Łukasz Dziedzic said in an interview (in Polish, translation mine):
Letters give us plenty of information, but they do so in a way which is completely unnoticeable.</description></item><item><title>What makes a good file name</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-12-12-good-file-name/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 22:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-12-12-good-file-name/</guid><description>One of the topics included in a research data management workshop with which I am involved is &amp;#34;what is a good file name&amp;#34;. The question may seem trivial, but naming files is an everyday practice with real consequences on data usability that isn&amp;#39;t talked about very often.
When looking for existing recommendations, we found a popular presentation Naming Things by Jenny Bryan, a related presentation Project Structure by Danielle Navarro, and a colelction of File naming best practices from the MIT Libraries.</description></item><item><title>The search for a perfect note taking app</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-note-taking-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 17:50:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-note-taking-apps/</guid><description>A note taking app is essential: meeting notes, quick how-tos, sketches of ideas call for a simple and convenient tool. While note taking seems like a straightforward task, there is a surprising variety of programs, and it&amp;#39;s difficult to find a perfect one.
So far I&amp;#39;ve had good experiences with Bear, Joplin, and Emacs with Org Mode. However, none of them came close enough to perfection for me to stick with it and forget about others.</description></item><item><title>Combining nilearn plots</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-06-01-combining-nilearn-plots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 23:45:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-06-01-combining-nilearn-plots/</guid><description>Visual presentation of brain results should be clear for the viewer, but the exact kind of a plot will depend on the result presented (just a single, super-important cluster? a scattering of voxels? widespread network?). Still, preferences vary, and finding the right way to present a given result may feel almost like finding one&amp;#39;s own artistic voice.
For the last given example (widespread activation of multiple brain regions), I have grown to prefer a montage of slices, accompanied by a glass-brain showing selected cuts.</description></item><item><title>Matlab table &amp; string</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-matlab-table-string/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-matlab-table-string/</guid><description>In this post I am taking a closer look at tables and strings in matlab.
Matlab continuously evolves, and the two data types are fairly recent additions to the language: table was added in R2013b and string in R2016b. Table arrays store tabular data and can make its handling (sorting, filtering, joining etc.) much more convenient than &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; cell arrays. In a way, they are similar to dataframes known from R or python / pandas, although more basic.</description></item><item><title>Giving in to pyenv</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</guid><description>There are several ways of installing and managing python on macOS, and in this post I am taking a closer look at pyenv. The write-up is divided into two segments. In the first (which I called &amp;ldquo;life story&amp;rdquo; during writing) I explain why I was avoiding pyenv for a long time and what caused me to give in. The second is technical and provides a short reference for creating and using my current setup.</description></item></channel></rss>