<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matlab table &amp; string</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-matlab-table-string/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-matlab-table-string/</guid><description>In this post I am taking a closer look at tables and strings in matlab.
Matlab continuously evolves, and the two data types are fairly recent additions to the language: table was added in R2013b and string in R2016b. Table arrays store tabular data and can make its handling (sorting, filtering, joining etc.) much more convenient than &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; cell arrays. In a way, they are similar to dataframes known from R or python / pandas, although more basic.</description></item><item><title>Giving in to pyenv</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</guid><description>There are several ways of installing and managing python on macOS, and in this post I am taking a closer look at pyenv. The write-up is divided into two segments. In the first (which I called &amp;ldquo;life story&amp;rdquo; during writing) I explain why I was avoiding pyenv for a long time and what caused me to give in. The second is technical and provides a short reference for creating and using my current setup.</description></item><item><title>Working with Siemens physio (.puls) files</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-working-with-siemens-physio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 16:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-working-with-siemens-physio/</guid><description>Siemens Physiological Monitoring Unit uses its own format for data storage. Conveniently, it produces text files with a fairly simple representation, which should be easy to parse. I only worked with pulse oximetry, but similar rules should hold for other physio data. This is a compilation of external sources, own experiences and code snippets.
Toolboxes Before we dig into the files: you may find what you already need in one of the following toolboxes (with which I have no experience), both in Matlab:</description></item><item><title>Docker pruning</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-docker-pruning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-docker-pruning/</guid><description>Sometimes (especially after messing around with several different images) I get the „No space left on device” error when doing even the simplest of tasks (e.g. running a small container or trying to build a new one). This issue may be MacOS-specific. Finding a clear answer wasn’t straightforward, so below I summarise what I learned.
The problem boils down to the Docker’s disk image, located (on MacOS) under:
~/Library/Containers/com.docker.docker/Data/vms/0/Docker.qcow2 See Stackoverflow: What is Docker.</description></item><item><title>Inkscape + ImageMagick: a powerful combination</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-09-28-inkscape-imagemagick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-09-28-inkscape-imagemagick/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend Inkscape enough, either for assembling figures or for building posters. However, Inkscape on its own does not export to tiff. Luckily, this can be accomplished with ImageMagick. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe, and a sort of laudation for both programs.
Recently I had to rework a figure with a schematic of an experimental design. The first version was put together in PowerPoint, but we somehow lost the ungrouped source file, so I had to start from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Now listening: Metallica - S&amp;M2</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-09-02-metallica-sm2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-09-02-metallica-sm2/</guid><description>About a week ago, Metallica released the S&amp;amp;M2 album, a recording of their live performance with the San Francisco Symphony Orchestra from September 2019 (and a follow-up on a similar collaboration from twenty years prior, April 1999). In my opinion, the first metal musician was Wagner, so Metallica recording with a symphony orchestra should make perfect sense, yet I was never very fond of the 99 edition. The new one, though, made a huge impression: I was listening to Spotify at work and had to take a short break to focus on the music.</description></item><item><title>Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order game review</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-06-09-jedi-fallen-order/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-06-09-jedi-fallen-order/</guid><description>Recently, I completed the latest Star Wars game. I had a good time, but was left wanting more. Here&amp;rsquo;s my thoughts.
Introduction Star wars Jedi: Fallen order came out in November 2019 and most certainly it has already been reviewed left and right (and has an overall score of 79 on metacritic at the time of writing). Given that I don’t play many different titles, let alone finish them, I thought I could attempt a review of my own.</description></item><item><title>A new rabbit hole: sim racing</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-05-12-rabbit-hole-simracing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-05-12-rabbit-hole-simracing/</guid><description>Due to the COVID-19 pandemic and related cancellation of F1 season, sim racing has been receiving a lot of attention, and after a while I gave in and bought a wheel for my PC. In this post I summarise my initial impressions from Raceroom.
Hardware Dealing with hardware is unavoidable here - while in a real car the driver gets plenty of physical feedback from, well, being in the car, in sim car all sensations have to be conveyed either through the screen or through the wheel.</description></item><item><title>Python, Windows, and how times are changing</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-04-01-python-windows-changing-times/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-04-01-python-windows-changing-times/</guid><description>I started using Python in 2011, as part of my BSc curriculum in neuroinformatics (the introductory course was part of the first semester IIRC). The Faculty was running Fedora on all computers, and so was I on my personal laptop. Back then, the advice to people who worked on Windows was to try and avoid that, because things with Python and Windows were complicated.
The common Python on Windows advice soon changed to &amp;ldquo;install anaconda&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Meat</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-19-beyond-meat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-19-beyond-meat/</guid><description>Today I finally got to try the Beyond Meat burger at Krowarzywa. This was the second plant-based meat replacement I tried (after the Impossible Burger), but the first one I could get in Poland, which feels good. It was great.
Speaking of the patty, the outside look is the biggest giveaway. The taste is indeed very similar to meat, maybe seasoned in a slightly unusual way, but definitely believable. The texture is really great, not unlike coarsly ground beef.</description></item></channel></rss>