<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gaming on Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/tags/gaming/</link><description>Recent content in gaming on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/tags/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order game review</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-06-09-jedi-fallen-order/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-06-09-jedi-fallen-order/</guid><description>Recently, I completed the latest Star Wars game. I had a good time, but was left wanting more. Here&amp;rsquo;s my thoughts.
Introduction Star wars Jedi: Fallen order came out in November 2019 and most certainly it has already been reviewed left and right (and has an overall score of 79 on metacritic at the time of writing). Given that I don’t play many different titles, let alone finish them, I thought I could attempt a review of my own.</description></item><item><title>A new rabbit hole: sim racing</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-05-12-rabbit-hole-simracing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-05-12-rabbit-hole-simracing/</guid><description>Due to the COVID-19 pandemic and related cancellation of F1 season, sim racing has been receiving a lot of attention, and after a while I gave in and bought a wheel for my PC. In this post I summarise my initial impressions from Raceroom.
Hardware Dealing with hardware is unavoidable here - while in a real car the driver gets plenty of physical feedback from, well, being in the car, in sim car all sensations have to be conveyed either through the screen or through the wheel.</description></item></channel></rss>