<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Giving in to pyenv</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-03-19-giving-in-to-pyenv/</guid><description>There are several ways of installing and managing python on macOS, and in this post I am taking a closer look at pyenv. The write-up is divided into two segments. In the first (which I called &amp;ldquo;life story&amp;rdquo; during writing) I explain why I was avoiding pyenv for a long time and what caused me to give in. The second is technical and provides a short reference for creating and using my current setup.</description></item><item><title>Working with Siemens physio (.puls) files</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-working-with-siemens-physio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 16:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-12-17-working-with-siemens-physio/</guid><description>Siemens Physiological Monitoring Unit uses its own format for data storage. Conveniently, it produces text files with a fairly simple representation, which should be easy to parse. I only worked with pulse oximetry, but similar rules should hold for other physio data. This is a compilation of external sources, own experiences and code snippets.
Toolboxes Before we dig into the files: you may find what you already need in one of the following toolboxes (with which I have no experience), both in Matlab:</description></item><item><title>Python, Windows, and how times are changing</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-04-01-python-windows-changing-times/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2020-04-01-python-windows-changing-times/</guid><description>I started using Python in 2011, as part of my BSc curriculum in neuroinformatics (the introductory course was part of the first semester IIRC). The Faculty was running Fedora on all computers, and so was I on my personal laptop. Back then, the advice to people who worked on Windows was to try and avoid that, because things with Python and Windows were complicated.
The common Python on Windows advice soon changed to &amp;ldquo;install anaconda&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>