<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>food on Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/tags/food/</link><description>Recent content in food on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 19:15:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Culinary discoveries of 2023</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2024-01-02-culinary-discoveries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 19:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2024-01-02-culinary-discoveries/</guid><description>It&amp;#39;s time for yearly summaries, so why not make one like this?
Dish of the year: mapo tofu Tofu is not a meat substitute, it&amp;#39;s an ingredient on its own and it&amp;#39;s a delicious ingredient – J. Kenji López-Alt
The dish I enjoyed making and eating the most this year was mapo tofu. More speciically, my version of Kenji&amp;#39;s version of his mom&amp;#39;s mapo tofu (which in turn is a japanese variation on the traditional Sichuan dish).</description></item><item><title>Circular pour-over</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-12-09-pourover/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 23:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2022-12-09-pourover/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, James Hoffman posted &amp;#34;A better 1 cup V60 Technique&amp;#34;, an update to his &amp;#34;Ultimate V60 technique&amp;#34; adjusted to smaller servings. I was pleasantly surprised that the 1 cup technique is more simialr (very similar, in fact) to the technique I&amp;#39;ve been using for a long time; that is, the drip recipe from The Barn. Have we gone full circle?
The Barn was pretty much my gateway into speciality coffee, back during my university years (around 2015, probably).</description></item><item><title>Beyond Meat</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-19-beyond-meat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-19-beyond-meat/</guid><description>Today I finally got to try the Beyond Meat burger at Krowarzywa. This was the second plant-based meat replacement I tried (after the Impossible Burger), but the first one I could get in Poland, which feels good. It was great.
Speaking of the patty, the outside look is the biggest giveaway. The taste is indeed very similar to meat, maybe seasoned in a slightly unusual way, but definitely believable. The texture is really great, not unlike coarsly ground beef.</description></item></channel></rss>