<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>randomthoughts on Michał Szczepanik</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/tags/randomthoughts/</link><description>Recent content in randomthoughts on Michał Szczepanik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 22:45:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mslw.github.io/tags/randomthoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What makes a good file name</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-12-12-good-file-name/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 22:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2021-12-12-good-file-name/</guid><description>One of the topics included in a research data management workshop with which I am involved is &amp;#34;what is a good file name&amp;#34;. The question may seem trivial, but naming files is an everyday practice with real consequences on data usability that isn&amp;#39;t talked about very often.
When looking for existing recommendations, we found a popular presentation Naming Things by Jenny Bryan, a related presentation Project Structure by Danielle Navarro, and a colelction of File naming best practices from the MIT Libraries.</description></item><item><title>Dealing with arcane bullshit</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-07-arcane-bullshit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 22:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-07-arcane-bullshit/</guid><description>Being a young scientist, at times I find myself having to deal with some programing related arcane bullshit. This post is something I wanted to write about for a while.
Case 1: video stimuli The primary culprit in this case is Presentation software from Neurobehavioral Systems, which, fittingly for its name, is a software for rigorously timed stimulus presentation. To be clear - it&amp;rsquo;s a very good, very reliable program and it has been serving our lab well for several years.</description></item><item><title>Why blog</title><link>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-05-why-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mslw.github.io/posts/2019-11-05-why-blog/</guid><description>Why would I start a blog? List of reasons below.
To check out jekyll. At first glance it seems nice and elegant. To have an outlet for occasional bursts of creativity. Sometimes I feel like writing. Sometimes writing helps me organise my thoughts. To practice writing. I read a sound advice on some scientist&amp;rsquo;s blog (unfortunately can&amp;rsquo;t find it now) that scientists should blog, because they need to write a lot, and for that there is no better practice than writing itself.</description></item></channel></rss>